mondoweiss.net 2019-12-27

# Privacy Policy – Mondoweiss

_Updated May 25, 2018_

This notice falls under the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR).

## Who We Are

Mondoweiss is an independent website devoted to informing readers about developments in Israel/Palestine and related US foreign policy. We provide news and analysis unavailable through the mainstream media regarding the struggle for Palestinian human rights.

The website is fiscally sponsored by [The Center for Economic Research and Social Change](http://cersc.org/) (CERSC), a nonprofit organization that is tax-exempt in the United States under Section 501(c)(3) of the Internal Revenue Code. Contributions are tax-deductible in the United States as allowed by relevant law, and other jurisdictions may also have applicable law governing such donations.

**Our postal address:**  
P.O. Box 442380  
Detroit, MI 48244

## Our properties

This privacy policy covers the following Mondoweiss properties:

  * Primary website: [mondoweiss.net](https://mondoweiss.net/); 
  * Any sites launched on a sub-domain of mondoweiss.net;
  * Online store: [store.mondoweiss.net](https://store.mondoweiss.net/);
  * Fundraising portal: [mondoweiss.kindful.com](https://mondoweiss.kindful.com/)

## How To Contact Us

Email dave@mondoweiss.net if you have any questions or concerns about this privacy policy.

## Personal Data We Collect May Include

  * Email address;
  * Names;
  * IP;
  * Website URL;
  * Social Media handle;
  * Newsletter: opens, clicks, opt-ins;
  * Comments submitted by users;
  * Support inquiries submitted by email;
  * Information collected when you make a donation or purchase may include: Names, email address, mailing and billing addresses, phone number, credit card or bank information.

## Cookies

Cookies are “small pieces of data sent from a website and stored on the user’s computer by the user’s web browser while the user is browsing.”[[Wiki](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/HTTP_cookie)] Our websites, and the third-party services listed below, may use cookies to help identify and track visitors, their usage of our websites, and their preferences. If they do not wish to have cookies placed on their computers, users should set their browsers to refuse cookies before visiting Mondoweiss websites.

## Consent to Collect

We collect data from users that have created accounts with us on our websites. We ask for consent during the account creation process with a checkbox. A link to this page is provided during the account creation process. The legal basis for us to collect the data is to be able to provide you with a service.

## Your Data, Your Rights

  * You can request a copy of your data which we will provide within 30 days;
  * You can request your data to be anonymized which we will do within 30 days;
  * While we will do everything we can to keep our service secure, in the event of a data breach or misuse, we will inform our users of what happened and what we have done to put it right within 30 days.

## Services and Third Parties

Mondoweiss never shares or resells any of our data. However, we do use third-party services to store and manage data for the following purposes:

  * Email marketing;
  * Social media marketing;
  * Communications among Mondoweiss staff;
  * Fundraising;
  * Website analytics;
  * Merchandise sales

## Length of Data Collection

Mondoweiss will keep identifiable data for an undetermined amount of time or until the user asks us to anonymize and / or delete their data.

## Who Has Access to Our Data?

  * Data at Mondoweiss is not shared or sold with any third party.
  * Staff and contractors of Mondoweiss and our fiscal sponsor CERSC have access to users’ data for the purpose of providing services.

## Privacy Policy Changes

Mondoweiss may update or change this privacy policy at its discretion. Users are encouraged to check this page for updates. Your continued use of Mondoweiss websites after any change in this Privacy Policy will constitute your acceptance of such change.
